好的，你准备好了吗？
Okay, are you ready?
差不多吧
I guess.
加速
And speeding.
那是什么？
What's that?
我想从一些问题开始
I want to start with some questions.
哦，明白了
Oh, got it.
对你来说很难吗？
Is it hard for you?
从那以后，你是不是很难...
Has it been hard for you since...
嗯……
Mmm...
我认为不会像你想的那样，但是......
Not in the way that I think you would think it would be, but...
嗯，这几乎是常识
Uh, it's pretty much common knowledge
至少需要 20 个贝壳
that it takes at least 20 shells
才能建立一个社区
to have a community.
那是你生存所需的最低限度，所以...
That that's about the minimum that you need to survive, so...
我一开始觉得
I think at first
我在想我们不会成功的
I was thinking we're not gonna make it.
但有时你只需要无视这些规则
But sometimes you just have to disregard those rules
并想，“嗯，实际上，规则是"
and think, "Well, actually, the rule is
"我想过上好日子"
"that I want to be having a good life
“并且活下来，然后……"
"and stay alive, and...
不仅要生存，还要过上美好的生活
And not just survive, but have a good life.
说说现在的生活怎么样？
Tell me about what's life like now?
它……我？呃...
It... Me? Uh...
我欣赏它各种各样的美
I appreciate its different beauties,
但它......这不是我做事的方式
but it... it's not the way I would've done things
如果我还在组里的话
if I was still in the group.
但他们不在这里
But they're not here.
所以，这就是我有电动搅拌机的原因
So, that's why I have the electric mixer.
- 准备好？ - 嗯嗯
- Ready? - Mmm-hmm.
Ta-da!
我的意思是，我不想让我的声音出现在其中
I mean, I don't want my voice in it.
好吧，这取决于你
Well, that's up to you.
所以，别再问我问题了，这就是我要说的
So, stop asking me questions is what I'm saying.
哦！哦好的
Oh! Oh, okay.
你父母有工作吗？你见过厨师吗？
Do your parents work? Have you ever met a chef?
如果你打破这个会发生什么？
What happens if you break this?
你吃过覆盆子吗？
Have you ever eaten a raspberry?
嗯，那是什么感觉？
Um, and what was that like?
你要问我问题吗？
Are you gonna ask me questions?
你好？
Hello?
天啊，这很奇怪
Oh, man, this is weird.
我不希望我的声音在里面
I don't want my voice in it.
我该怎么问你问题？
How am I supposed to ask you questions?
现在实际上只有我们两个人
There are actually only two of us now.
我...
Myself...
...还有我的祖母，娜娜康妮
...and my grandmother, Nana Connie.
早在男女住在这里的时候，
Back when the man and the woman lived here,
我们有很多人
there were a lot of us.
更多的声音和气味
More sounds and smells
还有，呃，有很多东西可说
and, uh, things to say
因为有更多的人可以交谈
'cause there were more people to talk to.
- 舞台有了  - 好的！
- There... A stage. - All right!
我上去了
Ah! Up.
这几天比较安静
These days, it's quieter.
穿着鞋子的贝壳马塞尔
继续 给我点难度
Rolling. Give me some levels.
加大难度？就像...
Give... Give you some levels? Like...
只是，就像，谈谈比如......
Just, like, talk a little bit. Like, oh, uh...
- 你好，我的名字是... - 该死的
- Hello, my name is... - Darn it.
这不是我第一次这样做
It's not the first time I've done that.
我叫马塞尔，
My name is Marcel,
你可以看到我身体的一部分是贝壳
and I'm partially a shell as you can see on my body,
但我也有穿鞋子
but I also have shoes,
还有，嗯，一张脸
and, um, a face.
所以，我喜欢我自己
So, I like that about myself, and I like myself,
我还有很多其他优秀的品质
and I have a lot of other great qualities as well.
-这很棒 -好的
-That was perfect. -Okay.
这是现在野外的风声吗？
Is this the wild tone right now?
- 是的  - 呃
- Yes. - Ugh.
保持静止 30 秒
Just stay still for 30 seconds.
你要多久...
How long you gonna...
你想用这些做什么？
What are you trying to do with all this?
嗯...
Um...
我正在制作一个小纪录片
I'm making, like, a little documentary
然后发布到网上
that I might put online.
- 网上？ - 是的
- Online? - Yeah.
呃，你失去我了
Eh, you lost me.
啊
Ugh.
-你还好吗？-痒痒， 你在录像吗？
-Are you okay? -Itchy. Are you recording?
-是的 -现在？
-Yeah. -Right now?
-是的 -哦
-Yeah. -Oh.
嗯，我该怎么办？
Well, what should I be doing?
只是，好吧，不要做任何事情
Just, well, don't do anything.
做你平时会做的事，
Just do whatever you'd normally be doing,
就像我不在这里一样
like if I weren't here.
你从哪儿弄来的绳子？
Where'd you get the rope?
这个？呃，它……我……我给你看
This? Uh, It... I... I'll show you.
我来到浴室，看到这团卷发
I come to the bathroom, I get these curly hairs.
他们是最强的
They're the strongest
因为你必须解开它，
'cause you have to uncurl it,
但是，嗯，那么你可以看到它真的很长很结实
but, um, then you can see it's really long and strong.
但...
But...
喂，你笑什么？
Hey, what are you laughing at?
我们称它们为耐寒毛发
We call 'em hardy hairs.
这是植物园，
This is the arboretum,
社区保持活力的树木集合，
a collection of trees that a community keeps alive,
但我确实喜欢和他们交谈，
but I do like to talk to them,
植物喜欢
and plants like to have
听古典音乐
classical music played for them.
莫扎特和勃拉姆斯，音乐帮助他们更快地成长
Mozart and Brahms, it helps them grow faster.
这是我的面包房
This is my bread room.
嗯，这是一间卧室，
Uh, it's a bedroom,
但我睡在一块面包上，
but I sleep on a piece of bread,
所以我...
so I...
哇，对不起 他只是在打招呼
Whoa, sorry. He's just saying hi.
其实我
I actually
有打算养只狗狗
like the concept of having a dog.
哦，天哪，我能闻到他的脸
Oh, God, I can smell his face.
但我只是将一根头发系在一块棉绒上，
But I just tie a hair to a piece of lint,
我把它拖来拖去
and I drag it around.
我爱你
I love you.
来吧 来吧 就这样
Come on. Come on. That's it.
有时候，人们说
Sometimes, people say
我的头对我的身体来说太大了
that my head is too big for my body.
然后我说，“与什么相比？”
And then I say, "Compared to what?"
有时候，如果我没有办法挠痒痒，
Sometimes, if I don't have a way to itch my itch,
我唯一能做的就是站在那里
the only thing I can do is I just stand there.
我只是忍者痒痒...
I just let it get me and I just...
然后我就大声喊出来
I just have to scream it out.
他是你最好的朋友？
He's your best friend?
你不知道其他
Don't you know any other
人 或者...
guys or...
酷炫的东西？
Cool？
唔 我从没有一次性成功进球
Hmm. I never get it the first time.
没有
Nope.
哦，该死的
Oh, dang it.
哦！去！去！去！
Oh! Go, go, go!
繁荣！它在那里
Boom! There it is.
您错过了 100% 的未拍摄镜头
You miss a 100% of the shots you don't take.
哇 那是一个引用
Wow. That's a quote.
这不是我编的
I didn't make that up.
这是一位名叫韦德的著名体育运动员...
It's by a famous sports player named Wayde...
韦德·甘斯迪...
Wayde Gansdy...
它是什么？
What is it?
方法...
Ways...
方式...鲸鱼...
Way... Whale...
鲸鱼·根斯基
Whale Gensky.
你在想韦恩吗……根斯基 鲸...
Are you thinking of Wayne... Gensky. Whale...
韦恩……这会是他的名字吗？
Wayne... Could that be his name?
鲸鱼·摩托艇？
Whale Jetski?
不，不？
No. No?
- 唤醒......湖......杰克？ - 好吧...
- Wake... Lake... Jake? - Well...
韦恩·喷气机...喷气机...得到...
Wayne Jet... Jet... Get...
这是我的储备
This is my stockpile.
好的，我带你了解下这里的基本情况
All right, so, we got your basics here.
我有几个杏仁 我有一打花生
I got couple of almonds. I have a dozen peanuts.
基本上都是你的干货
It's basically your dry goods.
你有蔓越莓葡萄干
You got a craisin with the raisins,
但蔓越莓放在边缘上
but the craisin sits to the side
因为这是一种享受 呃...
because it is a treat. Uh...
是……这是吸入器吗？
Is... Is this an inhaler?
就像……就像幻灯片什么的……
It's like... It's like a slide or something...
就像，我甚至不知道这是什么
Like, I don't even actually know what it this is.
你从哪里得到的？
Where did you get that from?
来自一个在这里住了一晚的人
From one of the people that stayed here for a night.
-什么事？-你有没有从我这里拿走过东西？
Why? Did you take anything from me?
嗯……
Mmm...
你这是怎么回事？
What is wrong with you?
我不知道
I didn't know.
给我那个 我不知道那是什么
Give me that. I didn't know what it was.
所以，这些都是放在一起的部分
So, these are all the parts put together.
嗯嗯 然后现在呢？
Mmm-hmm. And then now what?
我要把它放到网上，
I'm gonna put it on the Internet,
人们可以观看它 哦
and people can watch it. Oh.
不好了
Oh, no.
你的汽水罐几乎是空的
Your soda can is almost empty.
哇
Whoa.
对不起 等一会儿
Sorry. Hold on one second.
好的
All right.
我不知道你为什么会...
I don't know why you would...
什么...什么在打扫房子
What... What is cleaning the house
如果她所做的只是移动东西，
if all she does is move things around,
并扰乱整个环境？
and disturb the entire environment?
她没有 她现在正在洗碗
She doesn't. She's doing dishes right now.
她是吸尘器的先驱
She's the harbinger of the vacuum.
我不能让她回家
I can't tell her to go home.
我的意思是，那是她预约的清洁工作
I mean, that's her scheduled cleaning.
但为什么？她是被雇佣的
But why? She was hired
就像Airbnb的女主人
by the lady that is, like, the Airbnb host.
什么？ ……Airbnb？
What? The... Airbnb?
-嗯，什么是Airbb？-清洁
Mmm, what is Airbb? To clean.
哦，就是你！哦，她是谁？
Oh, that's you! Oh, who's she?
哦……我不……
Oh... I don't...
哦，哇，等等，什么？
Oh, wow, wait, what?
那是在外面 是的
That's outside of here. Yeah.
不知何故，这已经变成
Somehow, this has kind of turned
像进电脑旅馆？
into like a computer hotel?
有点，是的 为什么决定...
Sort of, yeah. Why did you decide...
你为什么在这？
Why are you here?
我不得不搬出我的老地方，
I had to move out of my old place,
所以我会一直待在这里，直到我找到一个新的
so I'm staying here until I find a new one.
你为什么要搬出去？
Why did you have to move out?
这是个人原因
Uh, that's personal.
好的
Okay.
你从来没有和以前住在这里的人说过话？
You never talked to anyone who stayed here before?
呃……
Eh...
人们通常不会注意到我们
People don't usually notice us.
哦，该死的
Aw, dang it.
我得去看看娜娜康妮
I got to go check on Nana Connie
如果这位女士要用吸尘器的话
if this lady's gonna be running the vacuum.
这是漫游者
This is the rover. Ow!
这是一件好事，我不喜欢“关心”关心
It's a good thing I don't, like, "care" care
关于这辆车，因为我不能
about this car because I can't
弄清楚我要去哪里
figure out where I'm going in this thing.
哎呀，那是什么？对不起
Oops, what was that? Sorry.
不不不 亚瑟
No, no, no. Arthur.
希望她就在拐角处
Hopefully, she's right around the corner here.
她就在那里
And there she is.
我放心了
That's a load off.
你能在这里等一下吗
Can you just wait here for one sec
因为我觉得你带着相机一起，
because I do think that with you and with the camera,
- 只是我... 那我... - 好吧
- it's just I... That I... - Okay.
我只是想警告她 是的 好的
I just want to warn her. Yeah. Okay.
棕色的头发，他有眼镜
Brown head-hair, and he has glasses.
你要我离开吗？
You want me to leave?
不，不，不，不，不，不！我要你留下来，就是我...
No, no, no, no, no! I want you to stay is what I...
- 是的  - 小心点
- Yeah. - Just careful
- 你踩到那里  - 是的，我知道
- where you step. - Yeah, I know.
- 我刚带他过去  - 你在做什么？
- I just brought him by. - You're making what?
一部纪录片
A documentary.
就像...哦，就像一部电影，
It's like... Oh, it's like a movie,
但没有人有任何台词，
but nobody has any lines,
甚至没有人知道它是什么
and nobody even knows what it is
在他们制作的时候
while they're making it.
嗯……不是吗？
Mmm... No?
这是一种表达方式，是的
That's sort of a way to put it, yeah.
不，我只是在制作一个肖像录像片
No, I just am making a little video portrait.
- 关于马塞尔？ - 是的
- About Marcel? - Yeah.
- 一个……一部电影？ - 嗯，是的
- A... A film? - Uh, yeah.
基本是这样，有点像 它是...
It's like the truth, kind of. It's a...
这是关于马塞尔的真相吗？
And it's the truth about Marcel?
我的意思是，我希望如此
I mean, I hope so.
我想他真的可以旋转它，
I guess he could really spin it,
让我看起来像一个...
and make me look like a total...
所以，这里就是你的花园，对吧？
So, this is your garden out here, huh?
- 是的  - 美丽的
- Yes. - Beautiful.
谢谢你 谢谢你的香气
Thank you. Thank you for the aromas.
我的房子很受欢迎
My house was very popular.
我有很多朋友
I had lots of friends.
如果你当时告诉我，
And if you told me then,
多年前，
many years ago,
我会在花园里度过这么多时间，
that I would've spent so much time in a garden,
我会说：“你在开玩笑吗？”
I would've said, "Are you kidding?"
好的，你看到这些了吗？
Okay, you see these ones?
你可以感觉到它们
You can feel them.
它们还没有完全成熟，
They're not quite ripe,
但几天后，他们会的
but in a few days, they would be.
这并不容易
It wasn't easy.
我对农业一无所知
I didn't know anything about farming.
因为当这对夫妇还住在这里的时候，
Because when the couple still lived here,
总是有食物
there was always food.
在储藏室里，在厨房里，
In the pantry, in the kitchen,
到处都是食物
there were stacks here and there.
但是当他们离开时
But when they went away
食物消失了
the food disappeared.
所以，我不得不自学如何种地
So, I had to taught myself how to farm.
“播种、收割……”
"Planting, harvesting..."
她一直是位非常坚韧的女人
She's always been a pretty tough cookie.
一切对她都有用处
Everything has a function with her.
没有一个按钮可以用来装饰
There's no one button that's there for decoration.
- 你知道我的意思？ - 嗯嗯
- You know what I mean? - Mmm-hmm.
她就像一个锄耕机
She's just like a backhoe.
但我会说你真的可以看到她温柔的一面
But I will say you can really see her tender side
当她与虫子一起工作时
when she's working with the bugs.
她还好吗？
Is she okay?
是的 她没事
Yeah, she's okay,
她有点胡思乱想
she's a little loopy.
她的花蜜有点多
She had a little bit too much, uh, nectar.
维诺·菲奥雷，对吧，弗兰妮？
Vino Fiore, right, Franny?
我的社区发现了虫子
My community found the bugs
从深处挖出来的
to be deeply unlikeable.
好的，我们会把她放在阳光下
Okay, we'll put her here in the sun.
几秒钟后，她就会变干
And in a few seconds, she'll be dry.
但是康妮和他们中的许多人交上了朋友，
But Connie's made friends with many of them,
作为回报，他们实际上在她的花园帮忙
and in return, they actually help her with the gardening.
...起初，发现它们有点恶心
...at first, found them a little yucky
但现在我看到了他们的美丽
but now I see their beauty.
我受不了这件事
I cannot stand this thing.
因为他们翻土、松土
Because they turn the soil, they break it...
拥有它们真是太好了
It's wonderful to have them.
他的整个身体看起来就像他的裤子脱了
His whole body looks like his pants are off.
它让我想起
It reminds me
Whoopi Goldberg在姐妹法案中，
of Whoopi Goldberg in Sister Act,
美国黑人女演员、作家、创作歌手、脱口秀主持人，亦是美国娱乐界史上写下“演艺圈大满贯”的十五位艺人之一，
即奥斯卡金像奖（电影奖）、艾美奖（电视奖）、东尼奖（舞台剧奖）、格莱美奖（音乐奖）得主
她如何帮助他们涂鸦
how she helps them to do graffiti
以一种有意义的方式或其他，并且...
in a meaningful way or something, and...
哦，她飞走了
Oh, there she goes.
- 哎呀！ - 哦，哦，哦
- Oops! - Ow, ow, ow.
她走了
She's gone.
呃，有点
Uh, sort of.
哦，哇
Oh, wow.
这是什么，呃……这是什么？
What is, uh... What is this?
- 唔？ - 那是什么？
- Hmm? - What's that?
你现在和马塞尔在做什么？
What are you doing now with Marcel?
哦，我在拍电影
Oh, I'm making a movie.
呃……纪录片
Uh... A documentary.
- 关于马塞尔？ - 是的
- About Marcel? - Yeah.
一部纪录片？呃，电影？
A documentary? Uh, a film?
是的
Yeah.
-啊，马塞尔 -你记得的，娜，
Ah, Marcel. You remember, Nan,
我们刚刚就在谈论它
we were just talking about it.
是一部电影，
It's a movie,
我们正在一起做，但是...
and we're doing it together, but...
——我刚才说的  - 那就是你...
- what I just said before. - That's what you...
我们只是开了个玩笑
And we just joked about it.
- 是的  - 这是事实，
- Yes. - It's the truth,
但这是关于我的真相...
but it's the truth about me...
她丢了一小块……
She has lost a small piece...
...一个非常大的难题
...of a very large puzzle.
娜！
Nan!
娜娜！
Nana!
每周一次或两次，我会在这里找到她，
Once or twice a week, I'll find her in here,
在洗衣篮里打盹，然后……
snoozing in the laundry basket and...
她呆在这里不好吗？
Is it bad for her to be in here?
是不好，这不是最安全的地方
Yeah, it's not the safest place to be.
你知道，我表弟在口袋里睡着了，
You know, my cousin fell asleep in a pocket,
这就是为什么我不喜欢这句话，
and that's why I don't like the saying,
“一切都在洗涤中出来，”
"Everything comes out in the wash,"
因为有时它不会
because sometimes it doesn't.
或者有时确实如此，
Or sometimes it does,
他们就像一个完全不同的人
and they're just like a completely different person.
因为在那之后，
'Cause after that,
我表弟就坐在窗边
my cousin would just sit by the window
并等待消防车经过
and wait for fire trucks to go by.
猜猜我用什么把滑雪板绑在车上
Guess what I use to tie my skis to my car.
-什么？-一根头发
What? A hair.
猜猜我的...
Guess what my...
穿鞋的马塞尔贝壳
MARCEL THE SHELL WITH SHOES ON
猜猜……猜猜我的滑雪板是什么
Guess... Guess what my skis are.
-什么？-一个男人的脚趾甲
What? Toe nails from a man.
等等，等等
Wait, hold on.
所以，你告诉我有 84 个不同的人有
So, you're telling me that 84 different people have
刚看了？
just watched?
是啊，那不是很酷吗？是的
Yeah, isn't that cool? Yeah.
我的意思是……天啊
I mean... Geez.
什么？
What?
只是……哇
Just... Wow.
当你感到无聊时，你会做什么？
What do you do when you get bored?
嗯，我四处走动
Uh, I move around.
我可以 他有一点为了你而在演的意思
I could tell he's performing a little bit for you,
- 你知道？ - 嗯嗯
- you know? - Mmm-hmm.
达，达，达，达 你给他一个舞台
Da, da, da, da. You're giving him a stage.
这对他有好处
It's good for him.
一二...
One, two...
舞台让他感觉很好
The stage makes him feel good.
好玩 他需要那个
Playful. He needs that.
他无法得到那个
He hasn't been able to get that
因为其他人是从我们身边带走的
since the others were taken from us.
好的，所以你只是想让我从头开始吗？
Okay, so do you just want me to start at the beginning?
其实不知道怎么开始的
I don't actually know how it started,
但是男人和女人开始互相吼叫
but the man and the woman started to yell at each other
比他们彼此交谈的次数还要多
more often than they would talk to each other.
你会听到这些来自天空的巨大噪音，
You'd just hear these big noises from the sky,
有一次我表弟的房子倒塌了
and my cousin's house fell down this one time
当办公室的门被砰的一声关上
when the office door got slammed.
我们开始制定庇护计划
We started to have a shelter plan.
我们都去袜子抽屉，
We all go to the sock drawer,
每个人都在那里就安全了
and so everyone will be safe there.
这是一个星期天，
This was a Sunday,
大家聚在一起，
and everybody gets together,
我们以社区为单位观看了 《60分钟》
and we all watch 60 Minutes as a community.
《60分钟》：美国的一个新闻杂志节目，由哥伦比亚广播公司（CBS）制作并播出，自1968年开始播出，迄今已播出逾40年。
该节目制作品质精良，口碑上佳，是美国知名的电视节目，也多次获得奖项。
60分钟，...
60 Minutes, the...
是的 所以，这就是我们所在的地方...
Yeah. So, this is where we were...
- 还有... - 每周，你们所有人？
- And... - Every week, all of you?
是的 我们喜欢它
Yeah. We love it.
我们称之为“节目” 这就是我们多么喜欢它的原因
We just call it "The show." That's how much we love it.
莱斯利
Lesley.
莱斯利是谁？莱斯利秀
Who's Lesley? Lesley Show.
她喜欢莱斯利·斯塔尔
She likes Lesley Stahl.
美国电视记者，在她 50 年的新闻职业生涯中，斯塔尔报道了美国历史上的标志性时刻，如1972 年的水门事件丑闻、
1974 年尼克松总统的弹劾听证会、 1981 年对里根总统的暗杀企图以及 1991 年的海湾战争。
我是莱斯利·斯塔尔...
I'm Lesley Stahl...
她的报道让人大开眼界
She blows cases wide open,
她很有品味
and she's got class.
...今晚60分钟
...tonight on 60 Minutes.
但...
But...
我们可以看出有问题
We could tell that something was the matter
因为时钟开始滴答作响...
because the clock started ticking...
......那里只有我们两个人
...and it was just the two of us there.
这是一个很大的
It was a big one.
我们有...
And we had...
我们没有任何警告
We had no warning.
我们认为是
What we think is that
每个人都跑了
everybody scooted
到袜子抽屉里，然后，呃……
into the sock drawer, and, uh...
而那个男人只是...
And the man just...
...把所有的抽屉都扔进了一个手提箱
...dumped all the drawers into a suitcase.
然后他离开了
And then he left.
那就是……他们就这么搬走的
And that's... That's how they got moved.
我...
I...
哦...
Oh...
你要纸巾吗？
Do you want a tissue?
好的
Yeah.
你介意我进去吹鼻涕吗？
Do you mind if I just plop into it real quick?
可以
Sure.
好了
Shoot.
这可能是我们的最后一件事
This can be our last thing.
好的
Okay.
他们总是这样说
It's always what they say on the days
当你有
when you have
一种非常敏锐的迷失感
a really keen sense of being lost
或失去一些东西，
or losing something,
就...
that it...
常常感觉阳光最耀眼
It often feels like the sun shines the brightest.
然后第二天，
And then the next day,
有一个非常阳光明媚的日子，微风拂面
there was a really sunny day with a good breeze.
我只记得在想，
And I just remember thinking,
“如果我是别人，
"if I was somebody else,
“我真的会很享受这个 ”
"I would really be enjoying this."
嗯嗯
Mmm-hmm.
哇！哎呀
Whoa! Geez.
好的，就是这样
Okay, here it is.
告诉我一些关于你在这里画了谁
So, tell me a little bit about who you put on here.
我首先 画了最重要的，
I put, first and foremost,
我的父母，凯瑟琳和马里奥，
my parents, Catherine and Mario,
用一颗心彼此相邻
next to each other with a heart.
我的兄弟在这里和这里...
My brother is here and here...
...我把我的音乐老师，作曲大师
...and I put my music teacher, The Maestro.
哇！是的！
Wow! Yeah!
我喜欢，听起来像 轻拍
I love that one, it sounds like Taps.
“轻拍”是美国武装部队在举行国旗仪式和军事葬礼时发出的号角
是的 你想听轻拍吗？
Yeah. Do you want to hear Taps?
当然
Sure.
你感到生气吗？
Do you feel angry?
呃，我觉得生气
Uh, I just feel angry
是我们没有更好的告别
that we didn't have a better goodbye.
你会跟谁说再见？
Who would you say goodbye to?
我想说的再见
I'd like to say goodbye
是给我的邻居，科斯塔斯
to my neighbors, the Costas.
再见，科斯塔斯，
Goodbye, the Costas,
即使我们有语言障碍
even though we had a language barrier.
你是我的邻居
You were my neighbors.
你一直喜欢园艺
You always liked to garden.
再见，理查德，你是我们班最差的歌手，
Goodbye, Richard, you were the worst singer in our class,
但我喜欢你让我打断你唱歌的方式
but I loved how you let me cut you in line.
再见，安卡，
Goodbye, Anka,
你的时间感是最差的之一
your sense of timing is one of the worst.
再见，桑德拉，你是我最喜欢的作家
Bye, Sandra, you were my favorite author.
再见，金夫人
Goodbye, Mrs. Kim.
你吃辣椒片的时间
The time that you ate a pepper flake
它让你飞到墙上
and it made you fly into the wall
是最有趣但最严重的事故之一
was one of the funniest yet most serious accidents
我们中的任何一个人都曾目睹过，
any of us ever witnessed,
你以极大的优雅和勇敢承受了它
and you bore it with great grace and bravery.
再见，布拉德
Goodbye, Brad.
太感谢了
Thank you so much
把那块大理石滚进我的面包房
for rolling that marble into my bread room.
直到今天我还保留着它
I still keep it to this day.
是的 那……他们都在那里
Yep. And that... And there they all are.
- 猜猜我为什么笑得很开心  - 为什么？
- Guess why I smile a lot. - Why?
嗯，因为这是值得的
Uh, 'cause it's worth it.
嗯……呃，你在做什么？
Um... Uh, whatcha doing?
寻找公寓
Looking for apartments.
那么，今晚你有什么安排吗？
So, do you have any plans tonight?
不
No.
我要...
I'm gonna...
- 给我那个  - 不！不！
- Give me that. - No! No!
哇 马塞尔，看看这个
Whoa. Marcel, look at this.
它……我不是……等等 这对你来说正常吗？
It... Aren't I... Wait. Is this normal for you?
不，这永远不会发生
No, this never happens.
- 这太酷了  - 2200万？
- It's so cool. - 22 million?
太棒了
It's wonderful.
是的，它是，呃，广泛的... 广泛的情绪
Yeah, it's, uh, broad... Broad spectrum of emotions.
我甚至不知道有这么多人
I didn't even know there were that many people.
好的，现在跳得很厉害
Okay, now jump really hard.
你们见过贝壳马塞尔吗？
Have you guys seen Marcel the Shell?
这是一个 YouTube 视频
It's a YouTube video.
我叫马塞尔，
My name is Marcel,
我身体的一部分是壳
and I'm partially a shell.
我叫马塞尔，
My name is Marcel,
正如你在我身上看到的那样，我是一个贝壳，但是...
and I'm a shell as you can see on my body, but...
哦，太好了
Oh, so nice.
...作为豆袋？
...as a beanbag?
一个葡萄干
A raisin.
广受欢迎的网络角色
The wildly popular online character,
穿着鞋子的贝壳马塞尔...
Marcel the Shell With Shoes On...
马塞尔...
Marcel...
穿鞋的贝壳马塞尔
Marcel the Shell With Shoes On.
“当库什袭击时……”
"When the kush hit..."
“库什”？什么是库什？
"Kush"? What is kush?
我……它走得太深了，而且……
I... It goes so deep, and...
他们有纹身
They got tattoos.
就是这么多人，我...
It's just so many people, I...
我有点后悔这个纹身
I kind of regret this tattoo.
在这里
Here it is.
这就像一只蜗牛
It's like a snail.
嗯，刚在网上看到
Um, I just saw it online,
但第二天就超级浮肿，
but it was like super puffy the day after,
我不知道为什么，
and I don't know why,
纹身男说不出原因
and the tattoo guy couldn't say why.
然后，几个月后，
And then, a couple of months later,
我发现我...
I found out that I...
今天我要爆米花
Today, I'm going to be popping popcorn
用放大镜 所以现在我们有...
with a magnifying glass. So right now we have...
都有这些人，
There's all these people,
而且... 我们都在看同一件事，
and... And we're all looking at the same thing,
我们都在做同样的事情
and we're all doing the same thing.
我们在看大伙...
We're watching the guys...
很美丽 而且...感觉就像...
It's beautiful. And... And it feels like...
我甚至不知道如何描述它
I don't even know how to describe it.
感觉像是什么
It feels like something.
快走开！
Move, move, move!
真的很可爱
It's really lovely.
你还好吗？是的是的 我很好 我很好
Are you okay? Yes, yes. I'm okay. I'm okay.
那么，你会吃吗？
So, are you going to eat it?
这玩意儿能吃吗？
You can eat this stuff?
是啊老兄！尝起来怎么样？
Yeah, dude! What does it taste like?
哦，天哪，你会喜欢的
Oh, my gosh, you're gonna love it.
太好了，不是吗？
So good, isn't it?
这一切真的很有趣，
It's all been really fun,
让这一切发生，然后……
and having all this happen, and...
还有，呃...
And, uh...
你知道，感觉如此强烈，而且如此美好
You know, it's so big feeling, and it's so nice.
嗯...
Um...
放手吧！放手吧！
Let it go! Let it go!
另一部分是我想我发现
The other part of it is I think I find
我的思绪徘徊了一点，只是在想，
my mind wandering a bit just thinking,
我的家人会怎么想，
what would my family think,
并且真正注意到
and really noticing
他们不是来和我分享的
that they're not here to share it with me.
我很想知道什么...
I do wonder what...
我爸会说什么，
What my dad would say,
我妈妈会说什么，而且，是的......
what my mom would say, and, yeah...
我想他们会很喜欢的
I think they'd like it a lot.
哦！她走了
Oh! There she goes.
哦，漂亮
Oh, beautiful.
唔
Hmm.
像我这样的人应该还有很多
There must be so many others like me.
不可能没有，
It's impossible that there wouldn't be,
而不仅仅是我的家人
and not just my family.
他们在外面
They're out there.
某个地方
Somewhere out there.
每次我这样做，那只狗都会完全发疯
Every time I do this, that dog goes totally crazy.
他在天空中看到了真正优雅的东西，
He sees something truly elegant in the sky,
这是他的反应？
and this is his reaction?
多么可悲的白痴类型
What a sad type of idiot.
哇，这是……
Wow, this is...
嗯，是的，我认为这不会产生太大的影响
Well, yeah, I don't think that's gonna yield much.
不，对，但是...
No. Right, but...
- 大概  - 你知道...
- Probably. - You know...
怎么了？
What's the matter?
你认为他们可能在外面吗？
Do you think they could be out there?
呃，我是说...
Uh, I mean...
也许
Maybe.
好吧，我想就是这样
All right, I think that's it.
我们正在直播
We are live streaming.
我是否看着你，
And do I look at you,
还是我应该看这个？
or should I look right into the thing?
我 快，呃，不，相机
Me. Quick, uh, no, the camera.
它会拍照
It's gonna take a picture.
好吧，好吧……
Okay, well...
大家好 我是之前的马塞尔，
Hi, everybody. It's Marcel from before,
我正在录制这个视频
and I'm recording this video
因为我正在寻找我的家人
because I'm looking for my family.
他们最后一次见到这个人
They were last seen with this man.
他叫马克
His name is Mark.
他们从房子里消失了
They disappeared from the house
由一个名叫拉里萨的女人拥有
owned by a woman named Larissa.
这里是
Here it is.
我们所做的是管理物业
What we do is manage properties
在短期租赁市场上，
that are on the short-term rental market,
所以如果有人出城很长时间
so if somebody's out of town for a long time
只是想租一个地方一段时间，我们这样做
and just wants to rent a place for a while, we do that.
那你能给我她的号码吗？
So would you give me her number?
如果物业有问题，
If there's a problem with the property,
我可以派人出去
I can send someone out,
但我不能给你任何个人信息
but I can't give you any personal information.
嗯 嘿，你吃过覆盆子吗？
Uh-huh. Hey, have you ever eaten a raspberry?
你好？
Hello?
该死
Darn it.
去吧
Just go for it.
这就是他们的样子 嗯，就在这里，
This is what they look like. Uh, right here,
这里和这里
and here and here.
嗯，我做这个只是为了给你一个感觉
Um, I made this just to give you a sense
要注意的人
of who to be on the lookout for.
对不起 我想我需要一点帮助
Sorry. I think I need a little help here.
- 迪恩？- 唔？
Dean? Hmm?
哦，迪恩，来吧 因为你在做的事
Oh, Dean, come on. Because of what you're doing.
令人兴奋 这是一个很好的场景
It's exciting. It's a good scene.
你可以……你仍然可以拍摄它
You could... You could still film it.
你可以把东西留在这里
You can just put the thing, you know, on the thing.
如果我不在这里，你会怎么做？
How would you do it if I wasn't here?
有很多次
There's a lot of times
我只是没有得到我需要的东西
where I just don't get stuff that I need.
你在这里 就能拍到这些真实的东西了
You are here. That's actually what the truth of it is.
是的，但我不想参与其中
Yeah, but I don't want to be in it.
就这样吧，事已至此 已经没什么意义了
That's, like, defeats the whole point of this.
你知道吗，迪恩，你有没有想过...
You know, Dean, have you ever thought that...
你的生活可能不那么孤单
your life might be a bit less lonely
还能与他人相处更加融洽
and a bit more integrated
只要你花点时间与人们建立联系
if you took the time to connect with somebody
而不仅仅是制作关于他们的视频？
and not just make videos about them?
谢谢你
Thank you.
最后，这张照片在这里
And lastly, this picture here
显示了马克开走的汽车
shows the car that Mark drove away in.
它是蓝绿色的 Mishibibi
It is a teal Mishibibi.
- 三菱  - 密西比西
- Mitsubishi. - Mitsi-ibitsy.
- 还有... - 三菱
- And... - Mitsubishi.
它是什么？三菱
What is it? Mitsubishi.
三菱汽车
Mitsubatbitsubisy.
请留下任何提示或任何有用的评论
Please leave any tips or any helpful comments
在下面的评论区
in the section below.
谢谢你 祝你有美好的一天
Thank you. Have a great day.
更新，伙计们，我想我们找到了
Update, guys, I think we found it.
这是马塞尔的家 这是马塞尔·谢尔的家
It's Marcel's house. It's Marcel Shell's house.
你觉得你现在能进去吗？
Do you think you can get in there right now?
- 哦, 有人来了  - 快走
- Oh, someone' s coming. - Go.
我们得走了 关注更多
We got to go. Follow for more
- 名人之家  - 尽管继续
- celebrity homes. - Just keep going.
嗯
Huh.
他们是...
Are they...
他们是来帮忙的吗？
Are they here to help?
嗯……
Mmm...
呃...
Uh...
不要觉得这是特遣部队
Don't feel that this is the task force
我以前倒是这么希望
I was hoping for.
什么都没有
There's so much nothing.
“她是最棒的 ”
"She's the best."
“她”？什么？
"She"? What?
但是我爸爸有一双粉红色的鞋子 我爷爷也是
But my dad has pink shoes. So did my grandfather.
好可爱
So cute.
啊 和平
Ugh. Peace.
嗯，是的 显然是和平
Uh, yeah. Obviously peace.
就像...
Like...
尝试测试多么奇怪的事情
What a weird thing to try to test
看看有没有其他人加入
to see if someone else is into.
就像，我当然很平静
Like, of course I'm into peace.
不，对不起，我是一个真正的好战者
No, sorry, I'm a real war person.
不，实际上是战争
No, war actually.
我签署了我所有的私人信件，“战争”
I sign all my personal letters, "war."
“让战斗开始吧 马塞尔 ”
"Let the battle begin. Marcel."
啊!
Ugh!
你知道，
You know, there's...
这里没有能找到他们的线索
There is nothing in here about finding them.
还是一群人，
It's still a group of people,
但它是一个观众 它不是...
but it's an audience. It's not...
这不是一个社区 有...
It's not a community. There's...
哦！那车呢？
Oh! What about the car?
怎么说？
What do you mean?
马克开着一辆蓝绿色的车离开了
Mark drove away in a teal car.
我们可以去寻找 比如，如果我们找到那辆车...
So we can go look for it. Like, if we find the car...
我不认为这...
Yeah, I don't think that's like...
这不是办法...
That's not the way to...
哇！好吧，所以它实际上看起来甚至没有那么大
Wow! Okay, so it actually doesn't even seem that big.
我的意思是，它很大，但我们只需要做的是
I mean, it's big but what we just need to do
站得高
is get up high,
然后也许我们就能找到他的车了
and then maybe we'll be able to spot his car.
嗯……你的壁炉架是什么样的？
Mmm... What's, like, your mantel?
比如，当我需要查看整个地毯时，
Like, when I need to look out over the whole rug,
我站得很高 我站在壁炉架上
I get up high. I get up on the mantel.
你明白我在说什么吗？因为我能看到...
Do you see what I'm saying? 'Cause I can see...
是的，不，我明白了 是的
Yeah, no, I got it. Yeah.
太好了，所以我们只要站到顶点
Great, so we'll just head up to the top of this thing,
然后我们就能看到它
and then we'll be able to see it.
我们不一定能够
I don't think we'll necessarily be able
看见了 我其实不同意
to see it. I actually disagree.
我认为这不是一个好主意，因为
I don't think it's a good idea because
如果我们……如果我们没有，比如，一个计划，
if we're... if we don't have, like, a plan,
那么我们只是，有点，盲目飞行
then we're just, sort of, flying blind.
我们可能会浪费很多时间
And we might just waste a lot of time
-绕圈子 -把那个放在那里...
-going around in circles. -Just put that there...
-这是做什么的？-以防万一我们吵架
What's that for? It's just in case we get in a fight.
我们不会吵架的
We're not gonna get in any fights.
你说外面很危险
You said it was dangerous out there.
-有各种危险 -所以... 你知道还有什么吗？
It's dangerous in a different way, so... And you know what else?
我应该带上这根火柴
I should probably bring this match.
你不需要那个
You don't need that.
呃，再给我一分钟
Uh, just give me one more minute.
我需要个头盔
I need some sort of a helmet.
好的，你拿到了这本书
All right, so you've got the book.
你有一点葡萄干
You've got a little bit of a raisin,
我真的不认为你会吃
which I really don't think you're gonna finish,
但你可以去城里 去镇上
but you can go to town. Go to town.
另外，你有
Also, you have
两滴……
two drips of...
看这里 什么？
Look over here. What?
你有两滴水
You have two drips of water.
你有一个 LED 手电筒，以防停电
You got an LED flashlight in case the power goes out.
你只需要像这样踩它 看？
You just got to step on it like this. See?
看看它是如何...哇 什么？
See how it... Whoa. What?
对不起 但不要站在它面前
Sorry. But don't stand right in front of it.
最后，这是烟火
Finally, this is the sparkler.
你所做的就是点燃这一端，
What you do is you light this end on fire,
然后你退后一步
and then you step back.
这可以作为一个闪光灯，知道了吗？
This can act as a flare, all right?
-为什么我需要它？-你需要发出求救信号的时候用
Why would I need it? That's if you need to signal for help.
迪恩会把他的电话留给你以防万一
And Dean's gonna leave you his phone just in case.
-什么？不，我不会..... -谁会看到闪光？
What? No, I'm not. Who will see the flare?
我想起来了
You know what? Now that I'm thinking about it,
我们现在为什么不把滤锅放在你身上呢？
why don't we just put the colander over you now
如果你想？
if you want?
好的，怎么样？
All right, how's that?
你必须让我离开这里
You must let me out of here.
你想让艾伦和...
Do you want Alan in there with...
- 我的天啊  - 没关系
- Oh, my God. - It's okay.
-我很抱歉 -没什么大不了的，小问题
I'm so sorry. It's not a big deal. It's tiny.
唷
Whew.
我觉得我没事
I think I'm okay.
天，我很抱歉
God, I am so sorry.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
你每天在车里呕吐几次？
How many times a day do you throw up in your car?
有一辆车 那...
There's a car. That...
那是蓝绿色，但是，呃，但这更像是，嗯……
That's a teal, but, uh, but that's more like, mmm...
除了在照片上，我从没见过湖
I've never seen a lake except for in a picture.
我们就去看看吧
Let's do it.
呃，我想我要哭了
Uh, I think I'm gonna cry.
它非常漂亮
It's very beautiful.
湖中有喷泉
There's fountains in the lake.
还有一辆车 还有一辆车 还有一辆车 还有一个...
And another car. And a car. And a car. And a...
有很多地方可以纹身
There's a lot of places to get tattoos.
“心灵恋爱专家 ”哇，我敢打赌……哇
"Psychic love expert." Wow, I bet... Wow.
我可以去这其中一家
I could use one of those.
你想让她说什么？
What would you want her to say?
呃，我不知道
Uh, I don't know.
海里有更多的鱼
There's more fish in the sea.
是的
Yeah.
你以后肯定会很有钱
Look, you got a lot of smoocheroonies in your future.马塞尔口误，原词应该是Smackeroonies，美元或英镑
- 现在我就可以预见了  - 好吧
- I can see it now. - Yeah.
是的，正是
Yeah, exactly. Yeah, yeah.
哦，宝贝，宝贝
Ooh, baby, baby.
哦宝贝
Ooh, baby.
我在电视上见过人们接吻
I've seen people kiss on television.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
在这里，是吗？
Up here, yeah?
哦！是吗？哦，就是这个！
Oh! Is it? Oh, this is it!
- 就是这个  - 让我们来看看
- This is it. - Let's check it out.
哇，我们真的要上去了
Whoa, we're really going up.
上，上，上， 这个地方会很高
Up, up, up. This is gonna get high.
嗯嗯
Mmm-hmm.
哇
Wow.
山上的小点是什么？
What are all the little dots on the hills?
那些是房子
Those are houses.
全部？
All?
是的 跟你的房子一样
Yeah. Those are houses like yours.
真的吗？
Really?
那是什么？
What's all that?
这就是城市的其余部分
That's the rest of the city.
啊对 是的是的
Oh, right. Right, right.
我...
I...
我没办法了
I had no idea.
这就是城市的全部了吗？
Is this all there is for out there?
嗯嗯
Mmm-mmm.
这里就是城市的大半部分
This is like one part of one big city.
还有……但是，呃……
And the... But, uh...
但是还有其他很多大城市
But there are many big cities.
城市很多 就像你之前在视频里见过的那样
There's lots of them. I mean, you've seen, like, you know,
比如在电影里，你就会听到人们说“东京”和......
in movies and when it says, like, "Tokyo" and...
“南极洲”，都是不同的地方
Uh-huh..."Antarctica," those are all different places.
好吧
Oh. Right.
他们可以去的地方太多了
There's so many places that they could be.
你觉得还有希望吗？
Do you think it's impossible?
我不认为这没希望
I don't think it's impossible.
我认为那只是，呃...
I think that's just, uh...
看那位女士的衣服
Look at that lady's dress.
我知道 这太好了
I know. It's really nice.
-谢谢你开车 -今天过得很有趣
-Thanks for the ride. -Yeah. It was fun.
哦 快看
Oh. Look at this.
他们就在……他们在草坪上
They're right on the... They're on the lawn.
- 他们要来了  - 停下来！
- They came right up. - Stop it!
你不会明白的
【远处声音】
You wouldn't get it.
大家好 伙计们
Hey, guys. Guys.
我想成为第一
I wanna be first.
- 嘿  - 停下来！
- Hey. - Stop it!
不，不
No, no.
嗯...
Um...
你介意稍微移动一下吗
Would you mind just moving a little bit
所以我们可以把车开进去？
so we can pull the car in?
亚瑟
Arthur.
娜！娜！
Nan! Nan!
娜！
Nan!
- 娜！ - 这里
- Nan! - Yes.
我的天啊 娜，你是...
Oh, my God. Nan, are you...
我只是有点受伤... - 哦，我的上帝
I'm just hurt a little bit... - Oh, my God.
- ...但我没事  - 你是？
- ...but I'm okay. - You are?
请只是...
Please just...
把你整个人都靠在我身上
Just lean your whole self on me.
把你所有的重量 别担心，我能承受
Put all your weight. Don't worry, I can take it.
我猜……好吧
And I guess... Okay.
嗯，让我们放轻松
Uh, let's just take it easy.
我真的不确定到底发生了什么
I'm really not sure exactly of what happened
因为她不会告诉我
because she won't tell me.
可能只是她不记得了
It could just be that she doesn't remember,
我认为情况可能就是这样
and I think that's probably the case.
你要我停下来？
Do you want me to stop?
但是我能想到的过程
But what I've been able to piece together
是她确实被吓了一跳，然后她从烘干机上摔了下来
is that she did get startled, then she fell off the dryer.
不！不！亚瑟！
No! No! Arthur!
对不起 亚瑟，过来
Sorry. Arthur, come here.
- 亚瑟！ - 迪恩...
- Arthur! - Dean...
亚瑟！过来
Arthur! Come here.
他……他……他得走了
He... He... He has got to go.
我不能让他这样和康妮在一起
I cannot have him here with Connie like this.
不是我不喜欢亚瑟
It's not that I don't like Arthur.
停下，迪恩 我不是在开玩笑
Stop, Dean. I'm not kidding.
不要那么做
Stop that.
不！我的天啊！
No! Oh, my God!
- 不！不，别录！ - 亚瑟！亚瑟！
- No! No. Off! - Arthur! Arthur!
好的 多一点点
All right. A little bit more.
好的
Okay.
他是...，呃...
What's he, uh...
他被告了？
What's he being charged with?
什么？
What?
他要去监狱吗？
Is he going to the jail?
不
No.
哦 哦，呸 因为我很抱歉 我想...
Oh. Oh, phew. 'Cause I'm sorry. I thought...
我要带他去我妻子家
I'm going to take him to my wife's house.
呃……你……
Uh... You...
什么？
What?
嗯，我们最近分开了，
Well, we got separated recently,
所以这就是我留在这里的原因
so that's why I'm staying here.
我一直在寻找一个新的地方
I've been looking for a new place.
所以我住这了
That's why I'm here.
你为什么不告诉我这个？
Why wouldn't you tell me this?
呃，我不知道 我没想到
Uh, I don't know. I didn't think to.
好的
Okay.
我跟你说了这么多 我...
I told you so much. I...
所以...我正在制作一部关于你的电影
So... I'm making a movie about you.
我不会拍关于我的电影
I'm not making a movie about me.
但你也在这里 我在分享
But you're also here. And I was sharing.
你也没有想过要分享吗？
You didn't also think to share?
-不了 -然后你只是指向周围
-No. -And then you're just pointing that around.
我确实在考虑
I do think about it.
它不是...
It's not...
你为什么……你总是在拍摄吗？
Why do you... Do you always need to be filming?
不
No.
我想你会很高兴我在拍摄
I think you'll be glad I have it, though.
我们一起完成拍摄
We have it.
嗯
Uh-huh.
稍等
Hold on.
我们可以暂停制作好的视频吗
Can we pause the videos that we made
这样人们就看不到这部分了，好吗？
so people can't see them, please?
是的，我可以把这部分拿下来
Yeah, I can take 'em down.
我只是不能让更多的人来家里
I just can't have more people coming to the house
就像今天发生的事情一样
like... Like how it happened today.
我不敢相信我让这发生了
I can't believe I let this happen.
你看到了，她睡了很久
Well, you know, she sleeps a lot.
而且她吃的也不多
And she hasn't been eating very much.
其实现在状态还不错 你只需要继续前进
It's looking good. You just gotta keep on moving.
你只是一个小...
You're just one more little...
让我做……我能做到
Let me do... I can do it.
她只是做不到
She's just not able to do
很多她曾经能够做到的事情
a lot of the things that she used to be able to do.
- 是的，好... - 疼
- Yeah, that's... - Hurts.
对不起，你关窗了吗？
Sorry, did you shut the window?
是的，我关上了窗户
Yes, I shut the window.
不要帮我 我不需要帮助
Don't help me here. I don't need help.
娜娜，我甚至什么都没做
Nana, I'm not even doing anything.
呃！
Uh!
溜冰场，
The skater rink,
通常只是假期的娱乐
you know, is usually just for the holidays.
- 想试试... - 我看起来怎么样？
- Want to try... - How am I looking?
你需要，呃，也许再多一两次
You need, uh, maybe once or twice more.
好的
Okay.
但我这么做只是为了...
But I set it up just to...
...试着让她开心一点
...try to cheer her up a bit.
加油 来吧，娜
Pump it. Pump it up. Come on, Nan.
向上
Up.
好的！
All right!
娜娜，加油
Nana, pump it up.
不，不 不，不，我不这么认为
No, no. No, no, I don't think so.
你不想溜冰吗？不，不
Don't you wanna pump it up? No, no.
当我说“果酱”时，你会说“娜” 果酱
When I say "jam," you say "Nan." Jam.
好吧，她不会再和我一起滑冰了，这是肯定的
Well, she won't skate with me anymore, that's for sure.
她不会喜欢了
Get into it, a little bit.
别来了
Stop it.
但你知道吗？
But you know what?
她……她真的很喜欢尘土
She... She really does like the dust.
对她来说，这很特别 她不是这里出生的
For her, it's special. She's not from here.
她来自车库 这就是为什么她有口音
She's from the garage. That's why she has the accent.
就是这种美妙的气味
It's this wonderful smell.
她通过大衣口袋来这里旅行
She traveled here by coat pocket
当她很小很小的时候
when she was really little.
我只是觉得...
I just feel...
所以我觉得这让她想起了家
And so I think it reminds her of home.
娜，看这个
Nan, look at this. Ready?
哦！
Oh!
康妮奶奶，我们得搬家了！
Grandma Connie, we need to move!
别走那边 这边走！
Not that way. This way!
快走！用漫游者逃！
Get it out! I'll get the rover!
我击中了吗？
Did I hit it?
不来这里？跟着我的声音来吧
Not coming over here? Come follow my voice.
- 你的左边还是我的左边？  - 你的左边
- Your left or my left. - Your left.
此时，好日子
At this point, the good days
已经逐渐离她远去了
are harder to come by with her.
他就在这里 他在沙发上
I mean, he's right here. He's on the couch.
是的，我正看着他
Yeah, I'm looking right at him.
糟糕的日子令人心惊
And then the bad days are just actually astounding.
哦！他会跳走
Oh! He can jump.
他在那里……他走了！
There he... There he goes!
啊，好吧，好吧  - 耶！
Ah, all right, all right. - Yay!
我尽量好好的对待
I'm trying not to treat her any differently,
但它让我保持警惕，确实如此
but it's, uh, keeping me on my toes, I'll tell you that.
等等，我要关了这个
Wait, I'm gonna close this.
哇，看看这个
Wow, look at this.
你好，马塞尔：我是纽约CBS新闻‘60分种’的制片人。
我听说你喜欢我们的节目。
- 你可能会感兴趣  - 是吗？
- You might be interested. - Right?
我们愿意....如果可能的话
制作一期关于你的节目....不知你是否介意
天啊
Oh, my gosh.
我就知道
I know.
与莱斯利·斯塔尔
With Lesley Stahl.
天啊
Oh, my gosh.
我们也会探索....任何线索.....有助于找到你的家人
啊 这是一个...
Ugh. This is a...
这是...
This is...
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
- 很神奇，不是吗？ - 嗯，是的，是的
- It's amazing, isn't it? - Mmm, yeah, yeah.
是真的...
It's really...
我们不能把这个给娜娜康妮看
We can't show this to Nana Connie.
绝对不
Absolutely not.
我可以要求他们
I mean, I could ask them to keep
低调录制，那么他们就不会
the crew really small, then they wouldn't make
-太过声张  -不 不行
-a big footprint. -No. No, no, no.
我能问他们有多少人会进来吗？
Can I ask them how many people would come in?
不，什么？
No. What?
我不冒这个险
I'm not taking the risk.
- 有很多... - 有什么风险？
- There are a lot... - What is the risk?
风险？看看娜娜康妮已经发生了什么
The risk? Look what already happened to Nana Connie.
“我们想知道你是否有兴趣
"We're wondering if you might be interested
“接受莱斯利·斯塔尔的采访 ”
"to discuss doing an interview piece with Lesley Stahl."
我们不能这么做，娜
We can't do it, Nan.
就是那个莱斯利吗？
The real Lesley?
-是的，这是真正的莱斯利  - 不要那样做
Yeah, it's the real Lesley. - Don't do that.
“如果你有兴趣，请告诉我
"Please let me know if you're interested.
“我们很乐意办成这件事”
"We'd love to make it work."
这种恢复的速度不够快，
This recovery is not happening fast enough,
现在她有态度了，我心疼
and now she has attitude, and I feel bad.
一旦她感觉好些，我们就会这样做
We'll just do it once she's feeling better
并四处走动
and moving around better.
你拿了几个？不要拿太多
How many of those do you take? Don't take a lot.
没拿，因为我不知道怎么用...
I'm not taking, 'cause I don't know how...
当我拿之前就不知道
when I'm gonna get another one.
这就是我的生活方式
This is how I live.
我们只是努力做事
We just had to work so hard just to do this,
为了寻找新的做事方式
just to find new ways of doing things
并学习如何独自生存
and learning how to survive on our own.
而且我猜是...
And I guess it's...
我可以有拥更多 所以我不想虚度
I don't wanna end up with less... than what I have.
我不能为你做这个决定，但是...
I can't make this decision for you, but...
你没有做决定 我已经知道怎么办了
No, you're not. I've already made it for myself.
-这是找到它们的好方法  - 不行
...this is a really good way to find them. - I said no.
和他在一起一点都不好玩，是吗？
He's no fun to be around, is he?
那边拐角有拼图纸片吗？
Do... Do you have any corner pieces over there?
我要你去做
I want you to do it.
娜，我已经拒绝了他们
No. Nan, no. And we already... We told them no.
但是你不想见莱斯利斯塔尔吗？
But don't you want to meet Lesley Stahl?
我们需要平静，娜娜
We need quiet, Nana.
我们不需要很多人来这里...
We don't need a lot of people coming in here and...
你不需要为我而平静
You don't... You don't need quiet for me.
-我不想平静 -哦
I don't want quiet. Oh.
-不了 -我认为你应该这样做
Nope. I think you should do it.
我们只是盲目地飞行
You know, we're just flying blind. I don't...
我甚至不知道应该在这里做什么
I don't even know what we're supposed to be making here.
这到底是什么照片？
What is this even a picture of?
你有蓝色的拼图片吗？
Do you have any blue pieces?
他似乎……他被束缚了，不是吗？
He seems... He's bound up, isn't he?
嗯
Mmm.
我觉得他害怕
I think he's afraid of
改变
change.
恐惧
Scary.
尤其是在我们近期经历了之后
Especially after what we went through.
但生活不会继续，除非...
But life's not gonna go on unless...
如果你不这样做
if you don't.
如果你不打开心结，对吧？
If you don't open up, right?
你知道吗，迪恩？
Do you know that, Dean?
呵呵呵
Heh, heh, heh.
我们当中谁不希望...
Who among us hasn't wished...
...我们可以读懂别人的想法？
...we could read someone else's mind?
确切地知道他们在想什么
Know exactly what they're thinking.
嗯，这是不可能的，当然……
Well, that's impossible, of course...
我要他...
I want him to...
我想让他融入生活，你知道吗？
I want him to dive in life, you know?
嗯嗯
Mmm-hmm.
我不会永远在这里 唔
I'm not gonna be here forever. Hmm.
你知道我的意思吧？
You know what I mean?
嗯，是的，我想他只是担心...
Uh, yeah, I think he's just worried that...
或许他会觉得...
Maybe he'll feel...
当你感觉好些时，他会有点放松
He'll sort of lighten up when you're feeling better.
-感觉好？-是的
Better? Yeah.
感觉好多了
Feeling better.
好 好 好
Better. Better. Better. Hmm.
滴滴滴 好了
T-t-t-t-t-tch. Better.
康妮？
Connie?
娜？
Nan?
这很奇怪，我都听到她说话了...
It's weird because I did think I heard her up. Listen...
什么...
What the...
娜
Nan.
你是……看看这有多有趣 看
Are you... Look how fun this is. Look.
- 你刚出来？ - 看，我忘记了这有多有趣......
- You're just out here? - Look, I had forgotten how fun...
你在外面多久了？
Yeah, how long have you been out here?
看，我可以...
Look, I can...
哦！怎么回事……
Oh! What is going on right...
娜，你真的...
Nan, you're really...
我必须努力实现我的目标，但是看，看，看
I have to work on my aim, but look, look, look.
是的，我看到了
Yeah, I see that.
我一直在努力得到它
I've been trying to get it.
我从来不明白这些话，但我可以做到...
I never understood the words, but I could do it with...
我不想超越自己
I don't wanna get ahead of myself,
但她似乎突然有了更多的能量
but she seems to suddenly have a lot more energy.
你知道那是什么吗？
Do you know what that is?
- 是... - 他们玩那个
- It's the... - They play that
- 运动前  - 是的，在运动之前
- before the sports. - Yeah, before sports.
这意味着运动开始了
It means the sports are starting.
你看什么样的运动？
What kind of sports do you watch?
他们喜欢追球或挤压球
They like running after balls or squash them.
踢
Kicking.
把球放在一张网上
Put them over, like, a net sometimes, they do that.
但是网有个洞，然后它掉出来了
But the net is a hole, so it comes right out.
对，所以就像，你为什么把它放回去？
Right, so it's just like, why do you put it back in?
- 真的很奇怪  - 我确实注意到，
- It's really strange. - I do notice,
我想，她肯定吃得更好了
I think, that she's definitely been eating better.
嗯 我最喜欢的
Mmm. My favorite.
不，这不是给你的
Nope, not for you.
娜，你真的
Bup. Nan, you really...
整个都吃完了？
Did you just eat that whole thing?
哦，是的，当然 我喜欢烤羊肉串
Oh, yes, of course. I love shish kebab.
- 哇  - 不，我们还是朋友
- Wow. - No, we're still friends.
你为什么要和她离婚？你老婆是不是...
Why did you divorce her? Was your wife...
她很棒 我们只是分开了
She's great. We just grew apart.
你还好吗？我完全没事
You okay? I'm totally fine.
你确定吗？也许你应该休息或...
Are you sure? Maybe you should be resting or...
-娜，也许我们会想到... -谁决定离开？
- Nan, maybe we'll think of...  - Who decided to leave?
- 你还是她？ - 两个都想离开
- You or her? - It was pretty mutual.
别骗我了 想分开也不会同时的
You don't fool me. It's never mutual.
而且她……她恢复了一些颜色
And she's... she's got some of her color back.
你坏了 你在做
You're broken. You're making
- 这部纪录片... - 哦，我的...
- this documentary to... - Oh, my...
那你就不用想她了？
So you don't have to think of her?
这是为什么？因为他伤心欲绝
Is that why? 'Cause he's heartbroken.
迪恩，你伤心吗？
Are you heartbroken, Dean?
他在笑，所以也许他没有那么伤心
He's laughing, so maybe he's not so heartbroken.
看着她 她已经完全
Look at her. She's just completely
-恢复如初 -完全恢复
bounced back. It's like... Completely.
- 100%恢复  - 哇
- 100%. - Wow.
我希望能遗传到这种基因
I hope I get that... those genes.
我就这么想
Because... I mean, that's not part of the deal.
你希望我快乐吗？
Do you want me to be happy?
- 是的  - 去接受采访吧
- Yeah. - Do the interview.
她会实现你的梦想
She got you there.
好的 为了你
All right. For you.
我喜欢你的勇敢
I like you brave.
来吧
Come on.
二...
Two...
呃，六……在左边，是的
Uh, six... Over to the left, yeah.
八
Eight.
再按绿色按钮
And now just the green button.
砰，宝贝
Boom, baby.
你能行的
You got this.
哥伦比亚广播公司
CBS.
哦，呃……喂？
Oh, uh... hello?
- 开免提 - 你好？
Put it on speaker. Hello?
你好，这是...
Hello, is this...
你好？这是莎莉吗？
Hello? Is this Shari?
是的！这是... 嗨，莎莉，呃，我是 马塞尔
Yes, it is! Is this... Hi, Shari, uh, this is Marcel.
这是迪恩 我也上线了
This is Dean. I'm also on the line.
嗨，很高兴与你们交谈
Hi, nice to speak with you guys.
很高兴与您交谈 嗯...
Nice to speak with you. Um...
对不起 前进 哦，对不起
Sorry. Go ahead. Oh, I'm sorry.
我只是说...
I just said it was...
和你说话也很高兴
That it's also nice to speak with you as well.
我也很高兴和你说话
It's nice to talk to you, too.
他表现得镇定自若，
He was acting calm and collected,
我就知道
and I knew he was, like,
严肃脸先生，镇定先生，
the front, Mr. Serious Face, Mr. Cucumber,
但内心 早就七上八下
but inside, butterflies.
绝对没错
Absolutely, yes.
谈论你的家人和你寻找他们的过程
Talk about your family and your search to find them.
有时我们会在拍摄时获得新的灵感
Sometimes we'll learn something as we're shooting,
这可能会带来新的发现
and that can lead to new discoveries.
你认为这是...
Mmm-hmm. And, uh, do you think it's...
有可能
It's a possibility that something could,
出现
uh, come from...
是的 但是我不敢保证
Yeah, I mean, there's no promises,
但如果你有线索，我们会看看...
but if you have information, we'll see where...
这个报道能引起的反响
Where our reporting leads.
嗯，还有，迪恩，我想问你的另一件事是，
Um, and, Dean, one other thing I wanted to ask you is,
我觉得这真的很有趣
you know, I think it might be really interesting
作为故事的一部分 你也将接受采访
to interview you as part of the story as well.
你觉得这样可以吗？
Is that something that you're comfortable with?
呃，我不知道
Uh, I don't know.
我一般躲在摄像头后面
I mean, I'm generally behind the camera.
啊!啊!
Ah! Ah!
有人不想被拍到 哦！
Somebody doesn't wanna do it. Oh!
我考虑好再回复你 你看这怎么样？
Uh, I'll get back to you on it. How about that?
唔？
Hmm?
这是一个小门铃
This is a little doorbell.
早安，娜
Good morning, Nan.
娜？
Nan?
嗯
Huh.
就一秒钟
Just one second.
早安，娜
Good morning, Nan.
- 今天就要开始了  - 是的
- Today's the day. - Yes.
哦，娜
Oh, Nan.
哦，不，我很好 我正要...
Oh, no, I'm fine. I was just going to...
你确定那是……它还疼还是……不，我要适应下
Are you sure that's... Does it hurt still or... No, adjusted.
已经好转了 看看
Getting better already. Look, look.
好的
All right.
我去给你拿点水
I'm gonna grab you some water.
哦谢谢 嗯嗯
Oh, thank you. Mmm-hmm.
这里有你的水
Got your water here.
冰凉的水，解渴
Ice-cold, thirst-quenching water.
谁想要它？水，水，谁要水？
Who wants it? A water, water, who wants a water?
谢谢你，马塞洛
Thank you, Marcello.
别客气
You're welcome.
有莱斯利·斯塔尔的一天
Quite a day for Lesley Stahl.
肯定有暴风雨来袭
There's definitely a storm rolling in.
我能感觉到
I can feel it.
我能感觉到，因为我的壳感觉很紧
I can feel it because my shell feels tight.
我看起来很紧张吗？
Do I seem nervous?
- 紧张没关系  - 呃
- It's okay to be nervous. - Ugh.
我明白这一点
Let me get that.
是的，我想
Yeah, I guess.
呃...
Uh...
我...
I...
- 那是... - 什么？那是什么？
- Is that... - What? What is it?
那是那天晚上的烤羊肉串
That's the shish kebab from the other night.
她在哪？你知道她在哪里吗？
Where is she? Do you know where she is?
娜娜
Nana.
你没有问我就夺走了我的选票
You took away my vote. You didn't ask me.
我不敢相信你撒谎了
I can't believe you lied.
- 你骗了我，娜  - 你让我没的选...
- You lied to me, Nan. - You took my...
-你忽略了我的意见 -我没忽略你
You wrote me off. I did not write you off.
你问我了吗？不，你没有
Did you ask me? No, you didn't.
-所以呢？-你一直说不
So? You just said no
只要花60分钟 就结束了
Just 60 Minutes, end of story.
我为你的健康做出了决定，因为我很担心
I made a decision for your health 'cause I was worried
关心你
about you.
我应该去开门吗？
Should I get the door?
我想要这样
That's what I want.
嗯，我……我也是
Well, I... I want that too,
- 但这是... - 我想要的只是...
- but this is... - All I want...
- 娜  - 我所想要的
- Nan. - All I want
就是让那个你去试一试
is for you to try.
- 我想要你... - 不...
- I want you... - No...
娜...
Nan...
这是一个广阔的世界
It's a big wide world.
我不想失去一切
I don't wanna lose everything
就因为有某种希望 那已经过去了
in the hope of something. That's already gone.
如果你不这样做，你会伤到我的心
You break my heart if you don't.
有人在家吗？
Hello?
你可以去告诉他们取消这次采访
You can tell 'em we need to cancel
如果你想的话
if you want to do that.
好吧，有什么选择？
Well, what's the option?
- 迪恩？ - 嗯嗯？
- Dean? - Mmm-hmm?
你能别说话？
Please, can you shut up?
-马塞洛……-什么？
Marcello... Yes?
让我们忘记害怕
Let's forget about being afraid.
呃……莱斯利会害怕吗？
Uh... Is Lesley afraid?
嗯，不，莱斯利是无所畏惧的
Mmm, no, Lesley is fearless.
可能好也可能不好
It may be good, it may be not,
尽管去冒险吧
but just take the adventure.
不要拿我当拒绝生活的借口 好吗？
Don't use me as an excuse not to live. Hmm?
但如果...
But what if...
如果一切都变了怎么办...
What if everything changes...
再次？
again?
马塞洛，哦...
Marcello, oh...
是的
Yeah.
它会变
It will.
哦
Aw.
过来
Come here.
好吧，好吧……让我们开始吧
Okay, well... let's do it.
来吧，去吧，去吧
Come on, go, go.
是的
Yeah.
你好 进来！
Hello. Come in!
你好，很高兴认识你
Hi, it's so nice to meet you.
很高兴终于见到你
It's good to finally meet you.
- 我猜你是莎莉？ - 你有部相机
You're Shari, I presume? You have a camera.
哦，我确实有相机 好吧
Oh, I do have a camera. Okay, then.
我可以在你们
Is that okay? Can I film while you guys
- 布置的时候拍摄吗？ - 可以可以
- are setting up? - Sure, sure.
- 真的？那太棒了  - 哇
- Yeah? That's great. - Whoa.
先生们没有戴蜂香剂
Those gentlemen were not wearing bee-odorant.
- 哇，哇！哇！ - 哇！
- Whoa, whoa! Whoa! - Whoa!
- 你看见了吗？ - 我看到了
- Did you see that? - I did.
那些盒子在走路
Just those boxes walking.
然后在他们身后，还有人
And then behind them, there were men.
看看这里的马尾辫
Look at ponytail over here
她在四处寻找浴室
looking around for the bathroom.
尽量表现的不慌不忙
Trying to act like it's not an emergency.
就在那里！
It's over there!
你在……你对他做什么？
What are you... What are you doing to him?
现在，我只是给了马塞尔
Now, I'm just sort of giving Marcel
一点古铜色  为了前期准备
a little bit of bronzer just to kind of warm up.
痒痒的
That tickles.
我只是在这里做一点
I'm just gonna do a little bit here.
哦
Oh.
-对不起，我朝你打喷嚏 -现在把嘴巴闭上
Sorry, I spit on you. Close... That's okay. Close your mouth.
现在他上电视了
Hey, now look, now he's on TV.
现在他又回到了现实中
Okay, but now he's back in real life.
那边的看过来，现实生活，上电视
This guy over here, look. Real life, on TV.
哦，看那个
Oh, look at that one.
那是工具腰带
That's Toolbelt.
还有那个？
And that one?
那是耳机先生
That's just Mr. Headphones.
你想看看你长什么样吗？
Do you wanna see what you look like?
我的天啊 你看起来不休息吗？
Oh, my God. Don't you look rested?
是的，我看起来像只喝橄榄油
Yeah, I look like I, like, only drink olive oil.
这边的这个人，看
This guy over here, look.
现实生活，电视上 马塞洛，看
Real life, on TV. Marcello, look.
好的 你航班怎么样？
Good. How was your flight?
还行
It was okay.
你懂的，很漫长
Yeah? You know, long.
今天过的很快乐……
All right, well, we have a fun day...
娜娜，发出那个声音
Nana, make the noise.
嘀嗒-嘀嗒-嘀嗒-嘀嗒-嘀嗒-嘀嗒-嘀嗒-嘀嗒-嘀嗒-嘀嗒-嘀嗒-嘀嗒...
Tik-tik-tik-tik-tik- tik-tik-tik-tik-tik-tik-tik...
所有这些故事以及更多信息
All these stories and more
-尽在60分钟  60分钟 -嘀嗒嘀嗒
-on 60 Minutes. 60 Minutes. -Tik-tik, tik-tik.
马塞尔，我能让你尽快进入状态吗？
Marcel, can I get you to stand in real quick?
哦好的 呃，娜，呃，你会...
Oh, yes. Uh, Nan, uh, are you gonna be...
走，走 是的当然 去 好的
Go, go. Yes, of course. Go. Okay.
去 走过来
Go. Coming through.
我马上带他回来
I'll bring him right back.
- 是的  - 马上回来
- Yeah. - Be right back.
再见
Goodbye.
在现实生活中，
On real life,
在电视上
on TV.
哇，我想，呃……是的
Wow, I think, uh... Yeah.
这是我见过的最亮的东西
I think that's the brightest thing I've ever seen.
我……我知道你喜欢
I... I know that you like
适合在你影片出现的东西
these kind of things for your movie.
- 这可能很好  - 嗯
- It might... might be good. - Mmm.
前几天我发现了这个
I found this the other day.
嗯……来了
Mmm... Here it is.
这是关于季节变化的
It's about season changing.
这本书……这本书我用了很多很多年了
This book... This book I had for many, many years.
但我没有注意到
But I had not noticed
这... 这部分我想读给你听
this... This part that I would like to read you.
请
Please.
出自20世纪后半叶英国著名诗人、小说家、爵士乐评论家菲利普·拉金的诗歌"The Trees"<树木>
“树木开始落叶
"The trees are coming into leaf
“就像有人说的那样……”
"Like something almost being said..."
好的，伙计们，五到四分钟
All right, guys, five to four minutes.
四分钟，各位
Four minutes, everybody.
“最近的花蕾开始绽放并蔓延
"The recent buds relax and spread,
“他们的绿色是一种悲伤 ”
"Their greenness is a kind of grief."
我们重来一遍 尽量一遍过，拜托
Let's reset. Let's go to one, please.
“难道他们重生了
"Is it that they are born again
“然后我们变老了？不，他们也死了……”
"And we grow old? No, they die too..."
哦你好 你好 你很美丽
Oh, hello. Hello. You are beautiful.
“他们每年都有新的装扮
"Their yearly trick of looking new
“写在谷物的秸秆上 ”
"Is written down in rings of grain."
- 声音，请  - 现场请安静
- Sound, please. - Quiet on the set.
场记 B机位  准备
And mark. Camera B marker.
我们正在开机
And we're rolling. Rolling.
当你准备好了
When you're ready.
“然而，还未休憩的城堡仍在打谷
"Yet still the unresting castles thresh
“每年五月长得稠密茂盛 ”
"In full grown thickness every May."
还没准备好，不，我会留下来
Not ready, no, I'll stay.
好吧，如果你坚持
Well, if you insist.
“去年已经远去，他们似乎在说……”
"Last year is dead, they seem to say..."
慢点，拜托
Slow down, come on.
“重新开始……”
"Begin afresh..."
等等我 等等我
Wait for me. Wait for me.
“……重新，开始”
"...afresh, afresh."
- 莎莉，完成了吗？ - 是的
- Shari, done? - Yep.
我们完工了
We're done.
好吧，大家 这是对马塞尔的总结！
All right, everybody. That's a wrap on Marcel!
他们必须到达出口
I think they had to get to the outlet,
但我们可以让他们把它搬回来
but we can get them to move it back.
如果有东西移动而没人注意到
Yeah, but if something moved and nobody noticed
娜娜康妮，她可能在什么东西后面
Nana Connie, she could be behind something.
娜？
Nan?
有时她会去厕所
I just... Sometimes she goes to the toilet
并坐在篮筐上
and sits on the rim.
娜？
Nan?
- 你检查过她的房间吗？ - 不
- You checked her room, yeah? - No.
我们要过去看一下吗..
Yeah, do you want... I mean, should we go over...
哦，是的
Oh, yeah, yeah.
下一个...
Next...
唔
Hmm.
我很高兴能见到她
I'm glad I got to meet her.
我也是
Me, too.
她大概觉得累了
She probably felt tired.
尤其在采访前那兴奋之后
Especially after being very excited.
你以前有没有这样经历过
Have you ever done that before,
比如，当家里开派对的时候？
like, when there's a party in your house?
这时候最容易困倦
Sometimes it's easiest to rest
当你离开后
when you go off by yourself
你仍然可以听到派对的喧嚣
and you can still hear the noise of the party,
知道周围有这么多人，你会感到安全...
and you feel safe knowing that so many people are around...
然后这样可以休息一下吗？
Yeah. ...that you can have a rest?
嗯嗯
Mmm-hmm.
涂得挺好的 还有这边
That's good. And now this one.
BGM：奇异的恩典，世界上最著名的基督教圣诗之一，在信仰基督教国家的葬礼上较为常见
这是一个人理想中想要的奶奶
She was exactly what you would want a grandmother to be.
她有充满活力的过去
She had a... A vibrant past,
多姿多彩的生平
and a colorful personality,
她没有被生活磨平棱角
and she didn't get sanded down by life.
你好！
Hello!
- 你好  - 你好
- Hi. - Hi.
你怎么在树上？
Why're you in the tree?
- 对不起？ - 那是我的树
- Sorry? - That's my tree.
- 这是你的？ - 是的
- This is yours? - Yeah.
哦，对不起 看起来像是她的
Oh, I'm sorry. It looked like it was on hers.
并没有
Nope.
好吧，你介意我在这里呆一分钟吗？
Well, do you mind if I stay up here for a minute?
- 只很短的时间... - 我介意
- I'm just... It's a short... - I do mind.
我没有保险
I don't have insurance
我怕你在那出事
for whatever you're doing up there.
好的 下来了 对不起
Okay, coming down. Sorry.
- 好的  - 你摔倒
- Okay. - You fall,
出事故，但要我负责
something happens, I'm liable.
你究竟是在那做什么...
What is it that you're actually...
是不是……不是跟工作室
Is it... Not with a studio
- 或者，呃... - 不
- or, uh... - No.
哇，好吧
Whoa, all right.
好吧，我把她画的像个百吉饼
Okay, and I made her look like an everything bagel.
“好耶”
Perfect.
哦，该死的
Ow, darn it.
好像不行...
It doesn't seem to...
快走
No, no.
走开
No.
Nope.
我不知道你想要什么
I don't know what you want.
我帮不了你 不知道是什么
I can't help you. I don't know what it is,
她不在这里，所以你必须...
and she's not here, so you gotta...
走开
...go.
嘿
Hey.
- 你好吗？ - 嗯，早上好
- How you doing? - Mmm, good morning.
你能教我一首歌吗？
Can you teach me a song?
我不知道我会不会唱……
I... All I... I don't know...
可以吗？
Will you do it?
你想这样mmm-mmms吗？
Do you wanna do the mmm-mmms?
当然
Sure.
你都已经跑调了
Well, you're really not singing the note at all.
-你会跑调  -是啊，我要怎么唱？
-You can't sing any notes. -No, I can't. But how do I do it?
我教不会你唱
Well, I can't teach you how to sing.
我可以跟着你唱
You do it, and then I'll copy you.
错了
No.
好吧你...
Okay, you...
错了
No.
我真的不知道该怎么教你
I really don't know what to do with you.
我不得不说...
I gotta say...
每一句都跑调了
No, none of those are the right notes.
你喜欢半坐在椅子上吗？
Do you like sitting halfway on a chair?
回家好好想想
Uh, yeah, go home and think about it.
不敢相信
This is unbelievable.
我要怎么练习？
What can I do to practice?
她留下了每件东西
She just kept everything.
那么...
So, are...
你现在要去哪里？
So where you... You gonna go now?
什么？
What?
你不走吗？不
Aren't you leaving? No.
-不？-哦 不，我为什么要走？
No? Oh. No, why would I do that?
我猜因为手提箱和...
Well, I guess 'cause of the suitcase and...
我只是在找我的领带
Oh, no. I'm just looking for my tie.
哦 哦
Oh. Oh.
我要去哪里？
Where am I gonna go?
我不知道
I don't know.
你就是目的地，宝贝
You're it, baby.
好吧
Oh, okay.
嘿，迪恩 嘿，马塞尔
Hey, Dean. Hey, Marcel.
这是 60 分钟的莎莉
This is Shari from 60 Minutes.
我想告诉你采访很顺利
Um, I wanted to let you know that the interview went great.
我们一直在看样片
We've been looking at the footage
我想知道你是否愿意
and I'm wondering if you would be willing to do
改天再来做采访
another day of shooting with us.
我们已经有了一些发现
So, um, we've made some discoveries
我很乐意与你分享
that I'd love to share with you.
这一切都发生得很快，如果你能回复我
It's kinda all happening fast, so if you could get back to me
在收到这条消息后
as soon as you get this message,
我将不甚感激
I would really appreciate it.
希望能尽快和你谈谈 再见
Um, hope to talk to you soon. Bye.
两个月后
好东西都是小包装的……
Good things come in small packages...
还有老道的经验，但今晚你们会以新的眼光看到它
...an old idea, but one you'll see tonight in a new light.
在他接受的唯一一次采访中
In the only interview he's given
自从成为网络红人，
since becoming an Internet phenom,
贝壳马塞尔分享了他独特的观点
Marcel the Shell shares his unique perspective
有关我们习以为常的事物
on what we take for granted.
他为最寻常的事物增添了新的意义
He adds new meanings to the simplest of ideas.
马塞尔，一个 1 英寸高的贝壳，
Marcel, a 1 inch-tall shell,
提醒着我们社区的真正价值
reminds us of the true value of community,
友谊的巨大力量
the transformative power of friendship,
和网球最巧妙的用途
and the most ingenious use for a tennis ball.
但如果你想确定
But if you wanna make sure
你的停车位是否完全平坦
that your parking space is, like, perfectly flat,
不然你不会放任不管的
because otherwise, it's not gonna be where you left it.
不过我这没有模型展示
And... And I don't have the model...
多年来，马塞尔和他的奶奶康妮
For years, Marcel and his grandmother Connie
与他们的宠物皮棉艾伦一起住这座老房子
shared this old house with their pet lint, Alan,
以及不断搬迁的人类客人
and an ever-changing array of human guests.
我只是远离他们，然后...
I just stay out of their way and...
并躲开他们的视线
And stay out of sight, and it worked.
但一切都变了
But all that changed
当一位业余电影制作人搬进来时
when an amateur filmmaker moved in.
......一直都是这样 所以，我觉得
...so kind of on all the time. And so, I felt like
我就抓紧机会一直拍
I could just roll and roll and roll.
迪恩，你的第一印象是什么？
Um, Dean, what were your first impressions?
我想我对他印象 有...
Uh, I guess I was impressed with his, um,
比萨...
pizzazz...
- 他的小创意 - 哇
- ...his spark, you know? - Wow.
噗
Uh, pfft.
我喜欢
No, I... I like it.
也许你需要...
And maybe you needed...
需要联系，需要友情
Needed the connection, needed the friendship.
是的，也许你需要友谊
Yeah, maybe you needed the friendship.
马塞尔，你有多久没有见到你的家人了？
Marcel, how long has it been since you've seen your family?
我没有计时
Well, I don't do the clock
你们计时的方式
the way that you guys do the clock.
我觉得
Right. Uh, but I think
我观察树木的变化
I'm watching the changes in the trees and
已经盛开的花朵
the flowers that have bloomed
和已经枯萎的花朵
and the blossoms that have fallen.
再次含苞欲放的花蕾
The buds that have come and bloomed again.
所以我无法告诉你准确时间，但我，呃......
So I... I couldn't tell you, but I, uh...
我心中的空间一天天变得越来越大，越来越响亮
The space in my heart gets bigger and louder every day.
迪恩，你知道有多久了吗？
Mmm. Dean, do you know how long?
那是两年
It was two years.
- 两年  - 是的
- Two years. - Yeah.
哦，很高兴知道
Oh, that's nice to know.
鉴于马塞尔与我们分享的所有新信息……
Given all the new information Marcel shared with us...
……而他只是，就像那张男人一样的脸，
...and he had just, like the same kind of man face,
两只眼睛
like two eyes, that kind of thing.
一张嘴和所有的牙齿
A mouth and all the teeth.
...我们能够找到拉里萨·盖勒
...we were able to track down Larissa Geller.
我们在危地马拉的高地找到了她
We found her here in the highlands of Guatemala
在非政府组织的环保机构工作
working for an environmental NGO.
盖勒随后回家
Geller then returned home
并帮助我们找到了这个人，
and helped us locate this man,
她的前男友马克·布斯
her former boyfriend, Mark Booth.
我都不想这样做 你让我陷入了困境...
I don't even wanna do this. You're really putting me in a tough spot here...
-我很快就会见到你  -拜托
All right, I'll see you soon. ...come on.
-好的再见 -这太荒唐了
Okay, bye. This is ridiculous.
等等，你还是……
Wait, are you still...
经过一些简单的介绍...
After some brief introductions...
- 这是马克  - 嘿，对不起
- This is Mark. - Hey, sorry.
这有点乱 我只是有点...
It's kind of messy. I'm just sort of...
- 我之前在打扫  - 好吧
- So I was cleaning earlier. - Right.
...搜索工作开始了
...the search efforts began.
我不知道 这是...
I mean, I don't know. This is...
我甚至不知道还能去哪找
I don't even know where else to look.
老实说，我不知道该怎么办 不知道那个地方
I honestly don't know what to do. I don't know the area.
绝对是这个包
This is definitely the bag.
所以……这是个好消息
So that... That is good news.
我不会再感到沮丧了...
I'm not gonna get... I'm not gonna start to feel down...
然后马塞尔听到了熟悉的声音
And then Marcel heard a familiar sound.
是的，然后你就过来了……
Yeah, and then you just came over...
我们的同事听到了争论
What our crew heard was an argument.
你所有的电子邮件...
You were on all of the emails...
但是马塞尔听到的...
But what Marcel heard...
……是警报声
...was the sounding of an alarm.
-当我是小孩呢？-是的
I'm a child? Yes.
袜子抽屉 我们检查袜子抽屉了吗？
Oh, dur, the sock drawer. Did we check the sock drawer?
他知道会发出警报
An alarm he knew would send
这是贝壳们的庇护所计划
any shells into a shelter plan.
天啊，到了！
Geez, it's over here!
大家好！这边！在这里，我要跑快点
Hey, guys! Over here! Over here, I need a boost.
我要去到上面
Hey, I need to get to the top. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
打开最上面的抽屉，有人...
Open the top drawers, somebody...
当心 要非常小心
Be careful. Be very, very careful.
打开 小心
Open, open. Careful.
接下来的画面我们不常见到
What followed was something we rarely see.
一家人团聚
A family reuniting.
老鹰乐队 - Peaceful Easy Feeling<平静轻松的感觉>
灵感来自作者看到一位年轻漂亮、戴着绿松石耳环的黑人女孩
Release Date: December 1, 1972
♪ I like the way your sparkling earrings lay ♪
♪ 我喜欢你闪亮耳环摇曳的的样子 ♪
♪ Against your skin so brown ♪
♪ 他们贴在你棕色的皮肤上 ♪
♪ And I want to sleep with you in the desert tonight ♪
♪ 我想和你在沙漠之夜共眠 ♪
♪ With a billion stars all around ♪
♪ 伴着璀璨星河 ♪
♪ 'Cause I got a peaceful easy feeling ♪
♪ 我感到平静而轻松 ♪
♪ And I know you won't let me down ♪
♪ 我知道你不会让我失望 ♪
马塞尔一直是个歌手
Marcel was always a performer.
♪ 'Cause I'm already standin' On the ground ♪
♪ 因为我已经站稳在这地面之上 ♪
他一直爱唱歌
He always wanted to, um...
凯瑟琳和马里奥
马塞尔的父母
他一直想站在舞台上，让人们开心和微笑
Always wanted to be on stage, make people happy and smile.
而作为他的母亲...
Mmm. And as his mother...
对不起
Sorry.
哦，妈妈
Oh, Mom.
哦，对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
我告诉过你，你会得到真正想要的
Yeah, I told you, you're gonna get right into the real stuff.
好的
Oh, yeah. Okay.
我们可以继续
Uh, well, we can do this thing,
或者稍后再进行采访...
pick it up later or...
我们谈些别的吧
Let's talk about something else.
去马里奥谈一会儿
Talk to Mario for a minute.
这真的很难
It's really hard.
马里奥
Mario.
是的 我……对不起
Yeah. I'm... I'm sorry.
我在想别的事
I was thinking about something else.
这就是我们贝壳一家
And that's us in a nutshell.
我只是……
Yeah, I just... I just was being...
大多数点子
Most of the innovations
是娜和我想出来的
Nan and I came up with, you know,
只是不再应用了
they're just not necessary anymore.
嗬！一，二，三，嗬！
Ho! One, two, three, ho!
话又说回来，其中一些真的起飞了
Then again, some of them have really taken off.
好的 非常感谢
Okay. Thank you very much.
看看你的样子
Look at you.
我想念你小小的脸，马塞尔
I missed your little face, Marcel.
我很想你 真想紧紧抱着你
I missed you so much. I just want to squeeze you.
我只是继续前进
Um, I'm just moving on.
更何况，我被美哭了
More so, I cried from the beauty.
噢，科斯塔斯先生，你把我弄的好害羞
Aw, Mr. Costas, you're making me blush.
你要把重心放在脚上......
Okay, but just put your weight on the front foot...
贾斯汀
马塞尔的兄弟
...然后你解开后面的那个  - 是的，是的，我能做到
...and then you unstick the back one. - Yeah, yeah, I can do it.
我知道 但你必须保持这样做
I know. Right, but you have to keep doing it.
我可以
I'm fine.
好吧，但是你知道发生了什么吗？
Well, all right, but do you see what's happening?
- 我知道  - 好的
- I know. - Okay.
她真的很棒，尤其是对于这么小的来说
She is really good, especially for such a little one.
但你知道这意味着什么吗？
But you know what it is?
她有你年轻时的那种东西
She has that thing that's like when you're young,
你不会恐惧，因为你还没有受伤
you have no fear 'cause you haven't injured yourself yet,
你甚至不知道风险是什么
and you don't even know what risk is.
你只是一直在飞驰
You just zoom around all the time.
马塞尔，我有耐心
Marcel, I'm being patient.
-好的 -马塞尔，来吧
Okay. Marcel, come on.
如果你想耐心等待...
If you're trying to be patient...
和我一起，摇晃你的小屁股
Come out here with me, and shake that little tush.
我会来的
Come on. I will.
我保证在溜冰场转一圈
I really promise I will take a turn around the rink.
-我只是在观察 -迪恩！
I'm just kind of observing. Dean, Dean, Dean, Dean.
-什么？ -拜托了
Yeah? Please.
这是我这一家子的习惯
This is the stock that I come from.
-迪恩 -你会看到一条直线血脉
Dean. You can see a direct line
通往娜娜康妮
to Nana Connie with this one.
你能告诉你的朋友马塞尔吗
Could you tell your friend Marcel
我不会永远等待，好吗？
I'm not gonna wait forever, please?
哇
Wow.
很高兴看到你和大家一起回来
It's nice to see you back with everyone.
Yeah.
随时欢迎你回到这里
You know, you're welcome back here any time you want.
-谢谢 -嗯嗯
Thanks. Mmm-hmm.
欢迎你随时来我家
You're welcome to my house any time you want.
你没有房子
You don't have a house.
我会尽快
I will soon.
我签了租约
I signed a lease.
-你们每个人... -我会来的
Each of you... Oh. Well, then, I accept.
一二三
One, two, three.
来吧，马塞尔 来吧 我们走吧
Come on, Marcel. Come on. Let's go.
我们要去滑冰
We're going ice skating.
我们要去溜冰场
We're going on the ice skating rink.
我刚刚见过你滑冰
Yeah, I saw you skating before.
一个人住了这么久，现在不一样了
It is different now after living alone for so long.
我发现有时在一个大群体中...
I find that sometimes being in a big group is...
这就是我想做的 我想滑下来
This is what I wanna be doing. I want to slide down.
好的 我不知道那是你
Good. I didn't know that that's what you were
试着做的 我以为你在问我怎么做...
trying to do. I thought you were asking me how I...
那对我来说太难了
...can be overwhelming to me.
各位 我要先学习一下
You guys, there's... I need to learn.
我需要一个可以静一静的地方……
I needed somewhere that I could come and just...
我发现自己来这里的次数更多了
I found myself coming down here more and more.
烘干机散发出如此美妙的气味
Such a lovely smell from the dryer sheets.
我喜欢，因为
And I... I like it because
有窗户的地方
there's a window
总是有一点缝隙
that is always opened a little crack there.
我站在那里
I would stand there,
想起我跟她说的事、问过她的话
and sometimes I'd tell her things, ask for advice,
或仅仅是自言自语
or just let sounds come out of my mouth.
有一天，我坐着在那
And one day, I was just sitting,
风吹进来
and the wind blew in,
它从我的头顶飞过
and it blew just over the top of my head in such a way.
一吹而过
And the wind blew over,
发出美妙的哨声
and it made a beautiful whistling sound.
这是什么声音？
What kind of noise is it?
等等，嘘，嘘 听
Wait, shh, shh. Listen.
你能听见吗？
Can you hear it?
这是风吹过我的壳的声音
That's it. That's going through my shell.
感觉她想要带我去一个地方
It felt just like her to lead me to a place
在那里我会体验到新鲜特别的东西
where I would experience something new and special.
它把我对一切的感觉联系起来
It connected me how I felt like to everything,
因为如果我不在那  这声音就永远不会存在
because if I wasn't there, the sound never would exist.
我觉得一切都成了碎片
And I felt like everything was in pieces,
然后我站在那里
and then I stood there,
突然之间，我们变成了一个大乐器
and suddenly, we were one large instrument.
我很喜欢去那里
I like to go there a lot
因为这让我想起
because it reminds me
我不只是一个孤立的个体
that I'm not just one separate piece
在这个地方晃来晃去
rattling around in this place,
在这里我是一个整体中的一部分
but that I'm part of a whole.
我真的很喜欢听到自己发出的声音
And I truly enjoy the sound of myself
与万物连结在一起
connected to everything.
我要让他出去 你准备好了吗？
I'm gonna let him out. Are you ready?
好的 放开猎犬！
All right. Release the hounds!
拜托，动手吧
Come on, do it.
我真的很高兴见到他
I'm actually really excited to see him.
它来了
Here it comes.
-你好 哥们  过来，布巴
Hi, bud! Oh, boo-boo. Come here, bubba.
你好吗，老哥？
How are you, pal?
哦，他记得你！
Aw, he remembers you!
嗯
Ah! Ugh. Ew.
你还记得马塞尔吗？
Oh, you remember Marcel?
你能闻到我
Oh, you smell. Oh, my goodness.
他有一种新的气味 是……他病了吗？
He has a new smell. It's... Is he sick?
我给他换了湿粮
I switched him to wet food,
这让他的呼吸变得疯狂
and it's made his breath go crazy.
现在是一种非常浓郁的香气
It is a very dense, very rich aroma.
- 亚瑟！ - 哇
- Arthur! - Wow.
所以，你们有湿狗粮
So, you guys got wet dog food.
- 是的  - 你有一个阳台
- Yeah. - You got a balcony.
- 是的，这里景色真好  - 真不错
- Yeah, we got the cool view. - That's nice.
你这里有一些花
I see you have some flowers here.
是的 他们很好看
Oh, yeah. They're nice.
我从一条自行车道上带来的
They're from, uh, a bike path.
我这儿前面有一条自行车道
There's a bike path that goes in front of my place.
嗯 这些花是谁给你的？
Uh-huh. Who gave you these flowers?
没人给我
No one gave them to me.
- 真的？ - 是的
- Really? - Yeah.
- 好吧  - 是我自己挑选的
- Okay. - I picked them myself.
真的吗？我们有过一个花园
Oh, really? 'Cause we had a garden
在那里我从没见过你采花
At our place, I never saw you picking any flowers.
我想让这里变得漂亮起来
I wanted to make the place nice.
有个朋友要过来玩
A friend was coming over.
- 啊，一个朋友  - 是的，我有个朋友
- Ah, a friend. - Yes, I had a friend.
什么样的朋友？
What kind of a friend?
- 她是个女孩儿  - 真的？
- She is a girl. - Really?
你要看看公寓的其他地方吗？
Would you like to see the rest of the apartment?
你想换个话题吗？
Would you like to change the subject?
是的，我想看看
Yes, I want to see it.
- 上车  - 哦谢谢
- Hop on. - Oh, thanks.
这里是我的房间
All right, so, here's my room.
这里的花更多
Oh! More flowers in here, huh?
是啊 这里花更多
Yeah, more flowers in here.
你从那条自行车道上采了不少啊
Hit... Hitting that bike path pretty hard.
这些是从农贸市场买的
Actually, those are from the farmer's market.
字幕翻译：Rodney
更多双语视频 请关注我的bilibili ：Rodney2012（或直接搜索“UID 7007408”直达）